Guide to the Hannah Campbell Papers 1958-1997 MS 2948
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
Hannah Campbell Papers
Bulk, 1958-1982
1958-1997
MS 2948
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
4.73 Linear feet (11 boxes)
Correspondence and papers of Hannah Campbell, a writer and magazine editor who lived in New York City from 1958 to 1982.
Biographical/Historical note
Hannah Campbell was born January 30, 1926 in High Point, North Carolina. She worked as a professional stenographer and legal secretary from the late 1940's through 1957. In 1958, she moved to New York City to pursue a career as a writer. She worked for various publications, including Cosmopolitan (1958-1961), Field & Stream (1963-ca. 1967), and Reader's Digest (ca. 1967-1982). While at Cosmopolitan, she began a regularly appearing column on the history of brand names, and in 1964 wrote a book on the same subject entitled Why Did They Name It...?. She also wrote free-lance articles and stories.
Never married, Campbell returned to North Carolina in 1982. She died in 2004.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists primarily of Hannah Campbell's personal correspondence with family members, spanning the years from the late 1950's to the early 1980's. Campbell's frequent letters include vivid descriptions of her personal and professional life and paint an interesting portrait of her daily life as a single professional woman in New York City during this time period. Of equal interest is Campbell's southern perspective on her experiences.
A smaller amount of business correspondence is also included, along with copies of Campbell's published articles and a copy of her book. Items of special interest include an article about an African-American-owned grocery store chain in Greesborok, NC. and correspondence regarding a proposed book on the subject of beauty for African-American women.
Arrangement note
This collection has been organized into the following four series:
Series I: Personal Correspondence
Series II: Professional Correspondence and Magazine Articles
Series III: Documents relating to Campbell's book, Why Did They Name It?
Series IV: Calendars
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Donated by Gilbert Edwin Southern, Jr., May, 23, 2013
Conditions Governing Access note
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
- Series I: Personal Correspondence, 1958-1982
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Campbell, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Frank Campbell, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Frank Campbell, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Frank Campbell, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Frank Campbell, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Frank Campbell, 1973-1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Parents, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Parents, 1961-1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Janet and Gilbert Southern, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Janet and Gilbert Southern, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Janet and Gilbert Southern, 1960-1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Janet and Gilbert Southern, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Janet and Gilbert Southern, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Janet and Gilbert Southern, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Janet and Gilbert Southern, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Janet and Gilbert Southern, 1972-1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Janet and Gilbert Southern, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Family & Friends, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Family & Friends, 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Family & Friends, 1965-1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Family & Friends, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Jo, 1958-1960 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Letters & Items, 1958-1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Letters & Notes for Memoir, 1958-1961 (Box 6A, Folder 1)
  - Letters & Notes for Memoir, 1962-1973 (Box 6A, Folder 2)
  - Letters & Notes for Memoir, 1962-1973 (Box 6A, Folder 3)
  - Letters Received, 1958-1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Series II: Professional Correspondence and Papers, 1958-1982
  - Professional correspondence, 1958-1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Professional correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Resumes and job applications, 1956-1967 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Articles and research work for Tom Fleming, 1958-1962 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Articles and research work for Tom Fleming, 1960-1962 (Box Oversize Small, Folder Campbell, Hannah)
  - Reader's Digest, philanthopic contribution program, 1968-1972 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Reader's Digest, covers, 1975-1999 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Published articles, trade magazines, 1959-1961 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Published articles, Cosmopolitan magazine, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Published articles, Cosmopolitan magazine, 1959-1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Published articles, romance magazines, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Published articles, Field & Stream magazine, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Magazine submissions, 1949-1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Romance manuscripts, 1961-1967 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Book Proposal: "Basic Beauty Book for Young Negro Girls", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Fiction Ideas, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Poetry, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Receipts and expenses, 1958-1962 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Series III: Documents relating to Campbell's book, Why Did They Name It?
  - Why Did They Name It? (third printing), 1973 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and royalty statements, Fleet Publishing Corporation, 1962-1985, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Reviews and promotions, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Reviews and promotions, 1970-1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Articles in Cosmopolitan magazine, 1959-1962 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "To Tell the Truth" television show, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Infringement issues, 1978-1990 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Book Research, 1960's (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Book Research, 1940's-1960's (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Book Research, 1940's-1960's (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Book Research, 1950's-1960's (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Book Research, 1960's (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Calendars
  - Calendars, 1958-1969 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Calendars, 1970-1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Calendars, 1977-1979 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Calendars, 1978-1982 (Box 11, Folder 4)